Jeremy Wuestefeld

Cell: 513-659-5835 | Email: <u>jwuestef@gmail.com</u> | Portfolio: <u>jwuestef.github.io</u> GitHub: https://github.com/jwuestef | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jeremy-wuestefeld

Junior Fullstack Developer

Experienced problem solver with a background working in fast-paced environments, who enjoys troubleshooting and solving puzzles. Passionate about emerging technologies, with a focus on the end-user experience. Collaborative self-motivator who gets excited about new challenges and learning opportunities.

Technical Skills

• Angular (*JS & 6*)

JavaScript

HTML5 & CSS3

Firebase

Node.js

Express

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

Git

MEAN Stack

QA Testing

Full SDLC

Work Experience

Junior Web Developer - Eleven Fifty Academy

11/2017 - present

- Principle architect and lead developer for a custom Learning Management System using Angular 6 and Firebase. Designed to organize course curriculum and projects, administer tests, and allow instructors to track student progress and provide feedback.
- Integrates with existing information system using a RESTful API.

Independent Web Developer

09/2017 - present

- https://jtaindy.com Developed custom website for local religious organization using Angular 5 and Firebase.
- https://doverecoveryhouse.org Worked on a team to build a custom website for a local non-profit women's recovery house using Angular 5 and Firebase.
- https://ganache.com Principal architect & team leader for a custom website for a local business build using Angular 4 and Firebase.

Police Officer - Crawfordsville Police Department

05/2014 - 04/2017

- Increased self-initiated field activity by 387% by multitasking and efficiently using worktime.
- Designed and built a custom program that cut time required to run license plates by 75%.
- Active Shooter Instructor trained 33 officers on the appropriate response to active shooter events to decrease civilian casualties.
- Restructured Reserve-Officer Board policies and procedures for the hiring, training, and retention of volunteer reserve officers.
- Fraternal Order Of Police (*Treasurer, Secretary*). Organized inaugural philanthropic 5k fundraiser that increased the Fraternal Order's fundraising by 300% over the previous year.

Project Manager - Indiana University

08/2009 - 05/2014

- Designed and built customized tutoring software for all 8 online-employees, which increased efficiency by 87.5% for each keyboard shortcut. Designed and built login/logout software for all online employees, and software to control 2 multimedia advertising display screens.
- Created and maintained a multi-file Excel spreadsheet to track 60+ employee schedules.
- Implemented hiring procedure each semester to filter 80+ applicants for approximately 15 positions.

Assistant Manager

- Awarded "Supervisor of the Year" in 2012, out of entire School of Science.
- Customer service and daily operations (of a 60+ employee center).

Calculus Tutor

• Tutored students in math, specializing in Calculus 1.

Education

JavaScript Accelerated Learning Program

Eleven Fifty Academy, Fishers, Indiana

• Police Basic Recruit

Indiana Law Enforcement Academy, Plainfield, Indiana

BS Mechanical Engineering, Minor in Mathematics

Purdue University - Indianapolis